### M. KENSEY BARKER

(703) 401-4969 | kenzrad@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/kensey-barker | GitHub: github.com/kenzrad | Portfolio: kenzrad.github.io/portfolio/

#### **SUMMARY**

Versatile technologist with 10+ years experience in STEM fields, including biotechnology, web development, e-commerce, and data analytics. Strong leader and adaptive learner with extensive project and people management skills. Expertise in JavaScript, jQuery, Node, and HTML/CSS.

## **SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS**

Agile Methodologies, Salesforce Commerce Cloud/Demandware (SFCC), Einstein Analytics, Google Analytics/Google Tag Manager, Azure DevOps, Git, MVC, JavaScript (jQuery, Express, Node, React, Vue), R, SQL/NoSQL, HTML, CSS/Sass/Bootstrap, REST and SOAP API, JSON/XML, VBA, Java

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Software Engineer**

NSTO, LLC (Need Supply Co. and Totokaelo)

July 2019-Present Richmond, VA

Web developer on an Agile team of two developers. Self-implemented two e-commerce sites on the SFCC platform. Regular collaboration with customer experience, site merchant, and creative teams. Continuous integration and customization of various plugins and tools (e.g., SOAP and REST API services, SFRA cartridges, analytics and tracking, SF Marketing Cloud, etc.). Triage, troubleshoot, and resolve bugs identified internally and by customers. Write, review, test, and deploy (utilizing Azure CI/CD) new code in sandbox, development, staging, and production environments.

# **Associate Group Leader, Molecular Genomics**

Pharmaceutical Product Development (PPD)

2010-2012, 2015-2019 Richmond, VA

Managed a team of  $\sim 15$  scientists in a fast-paced, deadline-oriented regulatory lab. Developed, managed, validated, and utilized various tools for complex scientific and statistical data analysis (VBA, SQL, R, various software). Compiled and reviewed validation and statistical reports. Worked closely with domestic and international clients, occasionally traveling to client sites for training and assay validation.

# Adjunct Instructor/Research Associate

2012-2016 Richmond, VA

Virginia Commonwealth University

Instructed Medical Microbiology Laboratory and GRE Preparation Courses to Undergraduate-Level students. Prepared lessons plans and classroom materials. Developed and evaluated exams and assignments. Provided guidance and mentorship to students. Designed and troubleshooted complex laboratory procedures. Conducted extensive research on molecular techniques. Maintained and evaluated large data sets using Microsoft Excel and R.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Certificate in Full Stack Web Development:** University of Richmond Trilogy Bootcamp, July 2019 **M.Sc. Biology** (Focus in Molecular Genetics): Virginia Commonwealth University, May 2014 **B.Sc. Biology** (Minor in Chemistry): Virginia Commonwealth University, May 2010